# **Hankook Lee**

#### PH.D STUDENT @ ALIN LAB IN KAIST

KAIST N1-917, 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, South Korea

■ hankook.lee@kaist.ac.kr | 🌴 hankook.github.io | 🖸 hankook | 🎓 Hankook Lee

## Research Interests

My research goal is to develop efficient and scalable deep learning algorithms that require few or no human annotation, and ultimately apply them to real-world applications with massive data. More specifically, my research interests lie in neural architectures, data augmentations, transfer/few-shot learning and un/self-supervised learning in various domains such as vision, chemistry, and tabular data.

## **Education**

## **KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)**

Daejeon, South Korea

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Sep. 2018 - Present

Advisor: Jinwoo Shin

· Advisor: Jinwoo Shin

## KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2018

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Computer Science (Double major)

Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2016

• GPA: 3.93/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

## **Publications**

C: Conference, W: Workshop, P: Preprint, \*: Equal contribution

# [C7/W] Improving Transferability of Representations via Augmentation-Aware Self-Supervision

Online

Hankook Lee, Kibok Lee, Kimin Lee, Honglak Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Dec. 2020

- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021
- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021 Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning for Reasoning and Perception

#### [C6] Self-Improved Retrosynthetic Planning

Online

Junsu Kim, Sungsoo Ahn, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2021

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021

#### [C5/W] RetCL: A Selection-based Approach for Retrosynthesis via Contrastive Learning

Online

Hankook Lee, Sungsoo Ahn, Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, Eunho Yang, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Aug. 2021

- International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021
- NeurIPS Workshop for Machine Learning for Molecules, 2020

#### [C4] GTA: Graph Truncated Attention for Retrosynthesis

Online

Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, June Yong Yang, Seohui Bae, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin, Sung Ju Hwang, Eunho Yang

Feb. 2021

• AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021

#### [C3] Guiding Deep Molecular Optimization with Genetic Exploration

Online

Sungsoo Ahn, Junsu Kim, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

Dec. 2020

### [C2] Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations

Online

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020

Jul. 2020

Received Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (2019)

Hankook Lee, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

## [C1] Learning What and Where to Transfer

Long Beach, CA, USA

Yunhun Jang\*, **Hankook Lee**\*, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2019

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2019

## [P] Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically

**Hankook Lee,** Jinwoo Shin

• arXiv preprint

## Work Experience\_

## **SAIT (Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology)**

Visiting student

• Developed ML-based retrosynthesis algorithms (AAAI 2021, IJCAI 2021 papers).

Suwon, South Korea Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

FrogramsSeoul, South KoreaResearch and Development EngineerAug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

• Built an automatic movie tagging system using movies' news/reviews based on Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA).

- Built a Scala-based movie rating prediction system based on non-negative matrix factorization.
- The incorporation name was changed to Watcha Inc. at 2018.

## Honors & Awards \_\_\_\_\_

2019	Winner, Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (ICML 2020 paper)	Daejeon, South Korea
2019	Travel award, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019	Long Beach, CA, USA
2013	Finalist, International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) World Finals	St. Petersburg, Russia
2012	1st Place (Grand Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional	Daejeon, South Korea
2010	2nd Place (Gold Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional	Daejeon, South Korea
2009	Gold Prize, Problem Solving Division, Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI)	Seoul, South Korea

## Services\_\_\_\_\_

2022 Conference Reviewer, ICLR 2022

2021 **Conference Reviewer**, ICLR 2021, ICML 2021, NeurIPS 2021

2020 **Conference Reviewer,** ICLR 2020, NeruIPS 2020

2020 **Journal Reviewer**, ACM ToMPECS 2020

2018 **Journal Reviewer**, ACM ToMPECS 2018

## Invited Talks\_\_\_\_\_

2021	<b>Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations</b> , Samsung Electronics DIT Center	Hwaseong, South Korea
2020	Learning What and Where to Transfer, Samsung Electronics DIT Center	Hwaseong, South Korea
2019	Learning What and Where to Transfer, Summer Annual Conference of IEIE	Jeju, South Korea
2018	Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically, NAVER Labs	Seongnam, South Korea

## Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_\_

2020	ia: "Semantic Segmentation and Object Detection", Samsung DS Al Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	rongin, South Korea
2019	TA: "Optimization and Regulaization", SK Hynix ML Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2019	TA: "Transfer and Multi-task Learning", Samsung DS AI Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2018	TA, Seongnam-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Seongnam, South Korea
2018	TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2017	TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Seoul, South Korea